Guide to the Gloria Coates Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Gloria Coates Papers
1970-1986.
Coates, Gloria.
0.5 linear ft (1 document box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0238
4079761
Gloria Coates is an American composer who studied at Columbia University with Jack Beeson and Otto Luening. These papers include correspondence, concert programs and business records related to her activities as director of the German-American Contemporary Music Series in Munich from 1970 through 1986.
Biographical Note
Gloria Coates was born in Wausau, Wisconsin in 1938, and won a National Federation of Music Clubs Composition Contest when she was twelve. After receiving a Masters of Music Degree in Composition at Louisiana State University, she studied with Jack Beeson and Otto Luening as a postgraduate student at Columbia University.
From 1971 to 1984 she produced the German-American Contemporary Music Series in Munich. The series received support from Alice M. Ditson Fund of Columbia University.
Scope and Content
The collection primarily concerns Gloria Coates's work in arranging concerts of American music in Munich. It consists of correspondence with performers and composers; financial documents related to the performances; concert programs, commentaries, and reviews; two photographs and one long-playing record.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically
Subjects
Columbia University.--Dept. of Music.; German-American Contemporary Music Series--Munich (Germany); Beeson, Jack, 1921-; Concerts--Germany--Munich.; Music.; Music festivals--Germany (West); Performing arts sponsorship.; Announcements.; Balance sheets.; Bills (financial).; Budgets.; Brochures.; Handbills.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Programs.; Receipts.; Resumes.; Tickets.; Composers.; Concert agents.; Impresarios.; Musicians.; Women composers.; Women musicians.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
05/01/87 M-87-05-01 Papers on music. Coates, Gloria Gift
Gift of Gloria Coates, 1987.
- Series I: Correspondence and related material, 1970-1986
  - Correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beeson, Jack, 1921-2010 (with related letters) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beeson, Jack, 1921-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Concert programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1986 concert programs, 1 long-playing vinyl record (Box 1, Folder 10)